Vinay Chanodkar

Dy. Manager - HR Reliance Jio infocomm Contact | (+91) **92018 22282, 810 963 9637** vinaychanodkar@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/vinaychanodkar/

Professional Summary

7+ years of experience in Human Resources Management (HRM) i.e. Talent Acquisition, HRBP, Talent Management, Employee Engagement, Attrition Management, Performance Management (PMS), key strategic HR initiatives, Stakeholder Management and Vendor Management and other HR operations.

Professional Experience

| Job Title | Organization | Location | Duration |
|-----------------------|--|----------|-----------------------|
| Deputy Manager HR | Reliance Jio Infocomm | Indore | Apr 2024 till present |
| Sr. Executive HR | Aditya Birla Housing Finance (Quess Corp. Payroll) | Indore | Oct 2022 to Apr 2024 |
| Deputy Manager HR | Skillventory | Indore | Feb 2022 to Oct 2022 |
| Assistant Manager BHR | Inspiaura | Indore | Feb 2017 to Dec 2021 |

Education Qualification

- MBA HR and Marketing (Full Time) | Devi Ahilya University, Indore | 2013 2015
- BE (Electronics and Communication) | Rajiv Gandhi technological University, Bhopal | 2009 2013
- XII (Higher Secondary School Certificate) | 2009

Roles and Responsibilities

Managing end-to-end employee life cycle for 700+ employees. Key responsibilities include:

Talent Acquisition

- Analysis of scorecard and prepare the Hiring dashboards, Offer Pipeline and weekly/monthly joining data for all the verticals
- Finding talent gaps and plan for fulfilment of critical role within the defined turnaround time (TAT)
- Coordinating manpower requisition and talent acquisition process using internet tools i.e. Naukri, LinkedIn, Company job post, and vendor coordination through HRMS.
- Managing live manpower dashboard.
- Responsible for end-to-end recruitment for Non-IT and Techno functional profiles that includes sourcing, screening, interviewing, selecting, documentation and offer process

On-Boarding

- Process includes offer releasing, engaging with offered candidate, asset allocation, formal induction
- Initiated weekly HR Connect campaign with new joiners helps them to understand HR policies and company culture
- Conduct new employee experience survey (30, 60, 90 days survey)
- Data analysis and visualization of survey and preparation of dashboard
- Initiated buddy up program and welcome mailers for the new joinee to facilitate smooth onboarding experience of new Joiners.

Employee Engagement and Communication

- Conducted the engagement surveys for more than 400+ employees
- Design and execute monthly engagement calendar covering employee connects and community celebrations
- Employee connect includes focused Group Discussion, Leadership Connects and One to One connects
- Conceptualizing and implementing monthly fun with learning activities along festive celebrations
- Initiated of a "Do You Know" mailers as an employee awareness program

Attrition Management, Employee Retention, and Exit Process

- Discuss the key factors of exit with employees under notice period.
- Analyzing monthly attrition trends for course correction.
- Managing exit to ensure the smooth transition of on notice employees.
- Conducting Exit Interviews to capture feedback on course correction.

Performance Assessments & Reviews | Talent Management

- Managing monthly and quarterly performance reviews
- Coordinating with leaders for Goal setting program
- Conducting Skip Level meetings to capture team feedback for People managers and facilitate feedback sharing to support managers to become better leaders.
- Fetching performance data through Power BI and initiated 'Rubaru' and 'Kill the Nil' sessions

HR Operations

- Managing Promotion, Increment and transfer letters through HRMS
- Managing monthly salary inputs to compensation team and coordinate for employee salary concerns
- Coordinate with MediAssist aligned TPA for employee health issues for quick response on cashless and reimbursement process
- Coordinate with People strong team for employee HRMS and attendance issues
- Coordinate with Sales Governance team for realizing hold incentives of employees
- Queck response to Key stakeholders i.e. Zonal manager and Head of departments
- Vendor coordination for offrole pay employees support and new offer release

Internships and Professional Certifications

- Data Visualization with Power BI from Great Learning, August 2023
- Excel Skills for Business: Essentials, Macquarie University, May 2020.
- Completed internship in Human Resource Management from Lotus Electronics in 2014

Personal Information

| Name | Vinay Chanodkar |
|--|------------------------|
| Date of Birth | 11-Aug-1992 |
| Marital Status | Single |
| Passport No. | M5262257 |
| Contact No | 8109639637, 9201822282 |
| Email Id <u>vinaychanodkar@gmail.com</u> | |

Vinay Chanodkar